<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrés Arau</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Andrés Arau</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracker of confirmed cases for covid19 in Mexico</title>
      <link>/post/covid19mx-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/covid19mx-tracker/</guid>
      <description>This interactive map is a personal and voluntary project that aims to track confirmed cases of #covid19 in each Mexican municipality. The map automatically updates in real-time using official data from the Mexican government.
Feel free to enther the map, click on a municipality to see how many of its residents have tested positive for covid19, or look at the charts that show the daily evolution of covid19 in Mexico</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up a website with R using blogdown, GitHub, and DigitalOcean</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>I am writting this because it took me some long nights and days to try to figure out how to get started with blogdown. Hopefuly this post helps someone just like these sources have helped me:
Yihui Xie’s fantastic blogdown book,Alison Hill’s amazing step by step,and, Collin Quirk’s super ueful guide to upload blogdown into DigitalOcean
In GitHUBCreate a repositary, name it as you want and enable a READMEClick on the green buton “Clone or download”In your terminalOpen git bash, select the local directory where you want to clone the GitHub repogit clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>MeI am passionate about data visualization, interactive maps, and the use of data innovative approaches to facilate ongoing learning and adaptation of development programmes.
I have lived in:Mexico, Canada, Spain, US, Sweeden, and UK.
And have worked in:Austria, Canada, Colombia, Cuba, Ghana, India, Kenya, Madagascar, Mexico, Mozambique, Nigeria, Peru, Sierra Leone, Spain, Sweden, United Kingdom, USA, Vietnam.
Have had the luck to work for these organizations in different projects:AshokaCarlos Slim FoundationDepartment for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy (UK)Department for International Development (UK)Fundacion IDEA /C230 ConsultoresInter-American Development BankInternational Atomic Energy AgencyInternational Fund For Agricultural DevelopmentOxford Policy ManagementThe Hunger ProjectWorld BankUnicefUnited Nations Development ProgrammeAlways walk together with:Marti :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>